John A. Seaverns Equine Collection MS275
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
John A. Seaverns Equine Collection
1864 -- 2001
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Webster Family Library
MS275
10.08 Linear Feet 5 record cartons, 2 letter size document boxes, 1 half letter size document box, 3 custom boxes, and 1 oversize box.
This collection contains ephemera, publications, and rare book and auction catalogs related to horses and horseback riding, primarily in the United States, dating from the late 19th century through 2001.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Webster Family Library, Cummings School of Veterinary Medicine, 2021, accession MS-2022-015.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in one series.
Custodial History
John A. Seaverns bequeathed his collection of equine and canine books and related materials to the Tufts University School of Veterinary Medicine in 1994. In 2021, the John A. Seaverns Equine Collection, consisting of ephemera, rare book and auction catalogs, and horse show programs, was transferred by John Bourgeois, Library Manager at the Webster Family Library, from the Webster Family Library to Digital Collections and Archives. Some of the books that were part of the original gift to the School of Veterinary Medicine were also transferred to Tisch Library in 2021.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains ephemera, publications, and rare book and auction catalogs related to horses and horseback riding, primarily in the United States, dating from the late 19th century through 2001. Ephemera includes fabric swatches, prints, supply catalogs, sheet music, scrapbooks, stamps, clippings, a record, and a flipbook. The collection also contains a small number of rare book catalogs related to dogs.
Content Warning
This collection contains ephemera with racist caricatures. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
Webster Family Library
- John A. Seaverns Equine Collection, 1864 -- 2001; MS275.000001; 10.08 Linear Feet 5 record cartons, 2 letter size document boxes, 1 half letter size document box, 3 custom boxes, and 1 oversize box.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains ephemera, publications, and rare book and auction catalogs related to horses and horseback riding, primarily in the United States, dating from the late 19th century through 2001. Ephemera includes fabric swatches, prints, supply catalogs, sheet music, scrapbooks, stamps, clippings, a record, and a flipbook. The collection also contains a small number of rare book catalogs related to dogs.
  Content Warning
  This series contains ephemera with racist caricatures. For more information on DCA's content warning policy please visit our website.
  - Rare book and auction catalogs, circa 1903 -- 1999; MS275.000003 (Box 3)
  - Rare book and auction catalogs, 1943 -- 2001; MS275.000004 (Box 4)
  - Rare book and auction catalogs, circa 1950 -- 2000; MS275.000005 (Box 5)
  - Rare book and auction catalogs, 1965 -- 2000; MS275.000002 (Box 1)
    Animal health and veterinary catalogs; ephemera, memorabilia, and rare book catalogs; tack, supply, trophy, and gift catalogs.
  - Ephemera, circa 1872 -- 1994; MS275.000006 (Box 2)
    Fabric swatches; prints of thoroughbreds; thoroughbred horse book catalog; patents related to saddlery; and "The Tellington Touch for Horses" booklets and VHS tape.
  - Ephemera, 1885 -- 1980; MS275.000007 (Box 6)
    Boston Horse Show Record of Directors scrapbook; prints; scrapbook of images of patented tack; publications; The National Trotting Association and Bell Bros. correspondence; metal box of address cards; flip book; clippings; and stamps.
  - Ephemera, circa 1907 -- 1997; MS275.000008 (Box 7)
    Rare book catalogs; sheet music; record; scrapbooks; prints; and publications.
  - Horse show programs, 1864 -- 1996; MS275.000009 (Box 8)
  - Horse show programs, 1933 -- 1991; MS275.000010 (Box 9)
  - Photographs of 205 Thoroughbred Sires, Volume I by L. S. Sutcliffe, 1928; MS275.000011; 1 Linear Feet (Box 10)
  - Photographs of 205 Thoroughbred Sires, Volume II by L. S. Sutcliffe, circa 1932; MS275.000012; 1 Linear Feet (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Thoroughbred Mares, Volume II by L. S. Sutcliffe, circa 1929; MS275.000013; 1 Linear Feet (Box 12)